Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

Software Engineer

@ hi@hadilq.com

hadilg.com

O Toronto, Canada

github.com/hadilq

@hadilq@androiddev.social

in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

Summary

A curious developer with over 17 years of experience in software development, where almost 7 years of his expe rience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student.

An Introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value-driven developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live. He values bayesian mindsets. He pursue reproducible, frictionless, consistent, and

A person whose goal is to surround himself with creative, clever, motivative and happy persons, so he can continuously learn more and more, not just learning, of course. In fact, he has valuable knowledge and sturdy knowledge transfer skills to share it. He knows that working with great minds will unleash his potential to be more

He's interested in decreasing build time, improving productivity of engineers by tooling. With Gradle's unregulated

world, who doesn't need a productivity engineer, or a passionate tool maker to automate everything in reach?

Experience

Productivity Engineer

at MobileLIVE Aug, 2022 - Present O Toronto, Canada

Promoted to Productivity Engineer to make tools and automate processes of the development life cycle to improve productivity.

- Investigated problems related to proxy and self-signed certificates in VPN networks, where by implementing a script, and a Jetpack Compose Desktop app, to install them automatically increased the build count in GE dashboard by 164%.
- Raised and implemented the need for Gradle Conventional Plugins to reduce duplication and errors, and also, improved consistency among Gradle configurations and versions of external libraries.
- Created a workflow POC in Gitlab to showcase how we can keep the code healthy by using Merge Trains and Merge request pipelines
- Decrease the time of running tests by 18% by using Robolectric.

Additional Technologies:

• Gradle Enterprise, Gradle Conventional Plugin, Jetpack Compose Desktop.

Software Engineer

at MobileLIVE

m Apr. 2021 - Aug. 2022

O Toronto, Canada

MobileLIVE is a Canadian tech-service provider unifying people, technology, and business to accelerate digital transformation. Over this time, he worked in Bell Canada as a full-time contractor. Bell Canada is subsidiary Bell Aliant provides services in the Atlantic provinces. It provides mobile service through its Bell Mobility (including Virgin Mobile Canada) subsidiary, and television through its Bell Satellite TV and Bell Fibe TV

Mission:

- Introduced RFCs to make technical decisions and steps to applying on any new idea.
- Added value by teaching and discussing SOLID principles, and best practices of modularization, feature
- Raised and implemented the idea of automatically cloning and building all the source code in the multirepo setup to reduce version conflicts, and improve code visibility for debugging purposes.

Technologies

- Kotlin Coroutines / Mockk, Mockito, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Lane based branching strategy, CI/CD
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jenkins, Slack, Branch.io, inVision, Dynatrace, etc.

Staff Android Developer

at iFood

m Oct. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

iFood is an ambitious project to build an entire food delivery ecosystem for all around the world. Currently, it's the biggest food delivery in Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, with 50+ million apps installed on Android devices alone. The Android project is highly modularized to make it possible for 50+ developers working on it fast.

- · Proposed and implemented composite build to handle dependency management in Gradle. It decreased the rebuild time while updating a library from more than 13 min to less than a minute.
- Implemented Android side of metadata project. Its purpose was gathering all information of our highly modularized Android/iOS projects in a dashboard along backend information.
- Proposed and applied a concept to move out the legacy code from the root module. It decreased the incremental build time of freed up modules by 55%
- Detected many ANRs and resolved them by applying architectural principles.
- · Wrapped up external libraries to better handling panic situations.

Technologies

- Dagger 2, Room, Kotlin Coroutines, Moshi, WorkManager / Mockk, Robolectric, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD. Gradle Enterprise
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Databricks, Firebase, Bugsnag, Logzio, etc.

Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

m Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey with 15+ million apps installed on Android devices alone.

- Improved the performance of loading feeds by at least a minute.
- Fixed multiple Memory leaks.
- . Known as "The man who broke the escape room" to emphasize his ability to think out of the box. Technologies
 - Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room / Mockito, Espresso, Robolectric, Jacoco, Ktlint, Fastlane, etc.
 - Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Dynamic Feature Module Delivery
 - Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma, New Relic, Firebase, Amplitude, etc.

Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

m Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

O Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions. TL;DR Mission: Increased the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.

Senior Android Developer

at Myket

Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users. TL;DR Mission: Implemented features in the Myket app store and started TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.

Java and C# developer

at Soha System

mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards. TL;DR Mission: Implementted Android and

Article / Repository

M 2023 Post: Dependency Inversion Principle

ດ 2023 Contributing to nixpkgs/androidenv: Nix is a language that is designed to have reproducibile output.

2022 Post: Logic Tree in Android
 2022 Sample App: Molecule sample app to solve some scoping problems in Android development.
 2022 Post: Reproducibility
 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Are feature flags, build variants, and sample apps related concepts?
 2021 FroAndroidDev post: Modularization tip: optimize the Root Module.
 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway. An improvement for Railway Oriented Programming in Kotlin.
 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway. An improvement for Railway Oriented Programming in Kotlin.

🗘 2021 Library: Happy is a library to auto-generate Kotlin code to make calling APIs more concise. 🗘 2020 POC: Rust Flutter Reactive is an idea to use Flutter as UI and Rust for the main project.

↑ 2020 Make Log4k Multiplatform: Simple logging library for Android, iOS, Mac, etc.
 ★ 2020 ProAndroidDev post: A/B Testing Myths
 ↑ 2020 Sample App: Provide a full implementation for a No-Framework Dependency Injection in Kotlin

 \bigcirc 2020 Contributing on Λ rrow Library: Λ rrow is a library for Typed Functional Programming in Kotlin

↑ 2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method
↑ 2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow
↑ 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM

7 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and Kotlin Coroutines

2020 Library: Simplifier for unnecessary complex lifecycles

2019 Math Library: Modularized, mathematical and multiplatform Kotlin library ☑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Logging in Kotlin • 2018 Log4k Library: Easy logging library, but unfortunately it's in Sheypoor repository

M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern
○ 2018 Sample App: Clean Architecture + RMVVM

M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava
M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events
O 2018 LiveEvent library: It's useful to propagate single event to View

Education Sharif University Of Technology

Payame Noor University

M.Sc in Physics B.Sc

in Physics

m Jul. 2007

Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

Tools / Skills

Android

Partially Open Source Mobile Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Anvil/Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/.. Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines Kotlin Compiler Plugin/KSP/. Compose/Data Binding/View Binding/...

Summary of why he's interested: It's partially open source OS Generally interested on Mobile Technologies.

Flutter

StatelessWidget/StatefulWidget StreamController/Isolates

Summary of why he's interested: Generally interested on all cross-platform and multi-platform solutions.

Rust

tonic/prost/openssl/tokio/flatbuffers/thrift Rc/Arc/Mutex

Summary of why he's interested: Rust's type system is what you need for scale-up. Borrow Checker restrictly stops any memory leaks. Bevy, and Dioxus frameworks look like good candidates for cross-platform solutions.

Docker

Buildkit/Compose/Cache Summary of why he's interested: Reproducibility is the key to productivity. Isolation is the key to reproducibility.

mkDrivation/mkShell Summary of why he's interested: Reproducibility is the key to productivity. Isolation is the key to reproducibility.

Architecture

NixOS/Nix Darwin

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture Unidirectional data flow Architecture MVVM/MVI/MVP/RMVVM

Principle Clean Code/SOLID Object Oriented Programming

Functional Programming Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle Design Pattern

Factory/Builder/Singleton/... Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/Delegate/...

Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

Android test library JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

Build Tool Gradle/Cargo/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

Command Line Tool grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/...

adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

Development Tool Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language

Java/Kotlin/Rust/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Ruby...

Operating System Linux(Nix OS/Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

- **Special Honor**
- 2020 Had an offer from MobileLIVE, Toronto, Canada- 2020 Had an offer from iFood, Remote
- 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada
- 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW, Porto, Portugal
- 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin, Germany 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor - 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in

Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume is in github Built on October 20, 2023